<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>links on Nicola Iarocci</title>
    <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/tags/links/</link>
    <description>Recent content in links on Nicola Iarocci</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nicolaiarocci.com/tags/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Activists Who Embrace Nuclear Power</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-activists-who-embrace-nuclear-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-activists-who-embrace-nuclear-power/</guid>
      <description>Today, my Sunday long-reading list included New Yorker&amp;rsquo;s The Activists Who Embrace Nuclear Power by Rebecca Tuhus-Dubrow. Can nuclear power possibly be a viable solution for climate change? Twenty or even ten years ago, my answer would have been a big fat No. Today? Not so sure anymore.
 Today, the looming disruptions of climate change have altered the risk calculus around nuclear energy. James Hansen, the NASA scientist credited with first bringing global warming to public attention, in 1988, has long advocated a vast expansion of nuclear power to replace fossil fuels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Minutes to Make You Love Classical Music</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/five-minutes-to-make-you-love-classical-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/five-minutes-to-make-you-love-classical-music/</guid>
      <description>I already mentioned what background music (or sounds) I like when I am coding. In that list, I included classical music. I know classical is not exactly a favorite. Not in my field, at least. I suspect the vast majority of people disregard it in advance, not really knowing what they&amp;rsquo;re missing out on, just because, well, you know, it&amp;rsquo;s dinosaurs stuff. If you are among them, you should reconsider and repent your sins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lasting Lessons of John Conway&#39;s Game of Life</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-lasting-lessons-of-john-conways-game-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-lasting-lessons-of-john-conways-game-of-life/</guid>
      <description>In March 1970, Dr. John Conway sent the &amp;ldquo;fatal&amp;rdquo; (as he later referred to it) letter to Martin Gardner. He was submitting ideas for Gardner&amp;rsquo;s Mathematical Games column in Scientific American.
The New York Times features a good article on the fifty-year parable of The Game of Life. What&amp;rsquo;s appreciable, they asked some of Life&amp;rsquo;s most steadfast friends to reflect upon its influence and lessons over half a century. Among them, Brian Eno, who, being Brian Eno, has some smart things to say:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Homebrew breaks your Python virtual environment</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/when-homebrew-breaks-your-python-virtual-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/when-homebrew-breaks-your-python-virtual-environment/</guid>
      <description>Ever had your old, trusty Python virtual environment fail on you? I sure did. Sometimes, when I activate or switch between virtual environments, I get the following error:
$ workon eve dyld: Library not loaded: @executable_path/../.Python  I never really took the time to look into it. When this happens, because I am in a rush (and because I am a lazy old fart), I shrug it off, recreate the virtual environment on the spot, and get back to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong opinions on software development</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/strong-opinions-on-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/strong-opinions-on-software-development/</guid>
      <description>After six years in the field, Chris has shared his strong opinions on software development practices, languages, and methodologies. I like his attitude. Willingness to continuously put one&amp;rsquo;s personal views under scrutiny, eventually adapting or even changing them as needed, is not a common trait. Not in our field. While I generally agree with most of his opinions, I feel the urge to comment on a few of them.
 Typed languages are better when you&amp;rsquo;re working on a team of people with various experience levels</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Unbundling according to Benedict Evans</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-great-unbundling-according-to-benedict-evans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-great-unbundling-according-to-benedict-evans/</guid>
      <description>As a non-native English reader, I had to look up the true meaning of &amp;ldquo;Unbundling&amp;rdquo; as a neologism. According to Wikipedia
 Unbundling is a neologism to describe how the ubiquity of mobile devices, Internet connectivity, consumer web technologies, social media and information access in the 21st century is affecting older institutions (education, broadcasting, newspapers, games, shopping, etc.) by &amp;ldquo;break[ing] up the packages they once offered (possibly even for free), providing particular parts of them at a scale and cost unmatchable by the old order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The unreasonable effectiveness of simple HTML</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-unreasonable-effectiveness-of-simple-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-unreasonable-effectiveness-of-simple-html/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve seen other articles pointing the finger at unnecessarily bloated websites. Terence Eden&amp;rsquo;s On the unreasonable effectiveness of simple HTML deserves mention, I think, for two reasons. First, the delivery is incredibly effective. Second, it is effective because of the storytelling.
By enveloping the message into an original short, touching story, he achieves two goals. First, he captures the reader&amp;rsquo;s attention; second, he makes the experience memorable. Please, go and read it; I&amp;rsquo;ll wait here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the short, tormented life of Phil Katz</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/on-the-short-tormented-life-of-phil-katz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/on-the-short-tormented-life-of-phil-katz/</guid>
      <description>Bless the Internet Archive and its Wayback Machine. With it, we can go back in time and read The short, tormented life of computer genius Phil Katz, an unusually detailed and accurate article published in the April 14, 2000 issue of the Milwaukee Journal Sentinel.
 When he was found dead April 14, Phil Katz was slumped against a nightstand in a south side hotel, cradling an empty bottle of peppermint schnapps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>