<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>links on Nicola Iarocci</title>
    <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/tags/links/</link>
    <description>Recent content in links on Nicola Iarocci</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 07:05:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nicolaiarocci.com/tags/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What getting old really feels like</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/what-getting-old-really-feels-like/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/what-getting-old-really-feels-like/</guid>
      <description>In a new study published in Ageing and Society, researchers Sam Carr and Chao Fang spent over 130 hours interviewing older people to understand what it&amp;rsquo;s like to get old and cope with loneliness. The Conversation UK features their report, appropriately titled Loneliness, loss and regret: what getting old really feels like.
 We found that ageing brings about a series of inevitable losses that deeply challenge people’s sense of connection to the world around them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASP.NET 6 Migration Cheatsheet and FAQ</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/asp.net-6-migration-cheatsheet-and-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/asp.net-6-migration-cheatsheet-and-faq/</guid>
      <description>David Fowler has a very informative gist up on GitHub. It&amp;rsquo;s titled Migration to ASP.NET Core. NET6 and it&amp;rsquo;s filled with details, recipes and FAQs on migrating an ASP.NET Core 5 web app to ASP.NET Core 61. The focus is on the new, streamlined hosting model, also known as Minimal APIs2. To be clear, You don&amp;rsquo;t have to move to the new model. As the FAQ section emphasizes:
 Do I have to migrate to the new hosting model</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The American Style of quotation mark punctuation makes no sense</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-american-style-of-quotation-mark-punctuation-makes-no-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-american-style-of-quotation-mark-punctuation-makes-no-sense/</guid>
      <description>Years ago, I translated an essay by Terry Windling, On Tolkien and Fairie-Stories, from American English to Italian. I remember arguing with the author about her use of periods in quotations. Each quotation would end with a period before the closing mark. I was puzzled. We don&amp;rsquo;t do that in Italy. More importantly, I read many English texts where the period was left outside the quotation itself. She insisted that her style was correct1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daft Punk&#39;s legendary Alive 2007 concert with remastered audio and 4K video</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/daft-punks-legendary-alive-2007-concert-with-remastered-audio-and-4k-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Sep 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/daft-punks-legendary-alive-2007-concert-with-remastered-audio-and-4k-video/</guid>
      <description>Someone did it &amp;ndash;the perfect Daft Punk tribute after their break up. Also ideal for those hard-coding sessions.
 For the first time in 14 years, experience Daft Punk like never before! The first professionally recorded live show; revived meticulously by remastering and restoring the audio and video. The Alive 2007 show is considered a staple in live performances featuring the signature &amp;lsquo;Pyramid&amp;rsquo; and groundbreaking visuals, which is now complemented by a fully remastered audio track which aims to maximize the experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get the Fucking Vaccine Already, You Fucking Fucks</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/get-the-fucking-vaccine-already-you-fucking-fucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/get-the-fucking-vaccine-already-you-fucking-fucks/</guid>
      <description>Wendy Molyneux, writing unabashedly for McSweeney&amp;rsquo;s, summarizes all I have to say on the COVID vaccine and never dared to say:
 You think vaccines don’t fucking work? Oh, fuck off into the trash, you attention-seeking fuckworm-faced shitbutt. This isn’t even a point worth discussing, you fuck-o-rama fuck-stival of ignorance. Vaccines got rid of smallpox and polio and all the other disgusting diseases that used to kill off little fucks like you en masse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance improvements in .NET6</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/performance-improvements-in-.net6/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/performance-improvements-in-.net6/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m pretty psyched about the upcoming .NET6 release. I&amp;rsquo;ve already touched on ASP.NET 6 Minimal APIs. Continuing on the long-established tradition, the team has also worked hard on the performance side of things. File IO, for example, is seeing impressive gains:
 For .NET 6, we have made FileStream much faster and more reliable, thanks to an almost entire re-write. For same cases, the async implementation is now a few times faster!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel is no cure for the mind</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/travel-is-no-cure-for-the-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/travel-is-no-cure-for-the-mind/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled upon a personal growth article this weekend, and that&amp;rsquo;s odd because I tend to stay clear from such things. Yet I found it quite relevant, so much that I thought I would share it (the delivery is also amusing, which is something new for this kind of content).
 It’s just another day… and you’re just doing what you need to do. You’re getting things done, and the day moves forward in this continuous sequence of checklists, actions, and respites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finland&#39;s intriguing take on the homelessness problem</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/finlands-intriguing-take-on-the-homelessness-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/finlands-intriguing-take-on-the-homelessness-problem/</guid>
      <description>In Finland, the number of homeless people has fallen sharply. The reason: The country applies the “Housing First” concept. Those affected by homelessness receive a small apartment and counselling – without any preconditions. 4 out of 5 people affected thus make their way back into a stable life. And: All this is cheaper than accepting homelessness.
 Finland&amp;rsquo;s take on the homelessness problem is remarkable and gives hope. I live in a small town where the problem is not as apparent as in, say, San Francisco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On GitHub Copilot</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/on-github-copilot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/on-github-copilot/</guid>
      <description>Like everyone else on the planet, I&amp;rsquo;ve been following GitHub Copilot since its launch. It is an impressive achievement and a remarkable milestone for the deep learning industry, that&amp;rsquo;s for sure. We are obviously at the early stages in deep learning applied to software development, and it is somewhat unsettling to ponder what the future might hold in this field.
Like many others, however, I worry about code quality issues and the risk of license infringements1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internet is Rotting</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-internet-is-rotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-internet-is-rotting/</guid>
      <description>Terrific piece by Jonathan Zittrain, on The Atlantic, on link rot and digital preservation. I love how well documented and informative it is. Yet, it remains perfectly approachable for both the non-knowledgeable reader and the technically savvy.
 Too much has been lost already. The glue that holds humanity’s knowledge together is coming undone.
 We need more content like this.
Subscribe to the newsletter, the RSS feed, or follow @nicolaiarocci on Twitter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proust&#39;s Madeleine Was Originally a Slice of Toast</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/prousts-madeleine-was-originally-a-slice-of-toast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/prousts-madeleine-was-originally-a-slice-of-toast/</guid>
      <description>A long-sought first draft of Marcel Proust&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;In Search of Lost Time&amp;rsquo; surfaced a few years ago. Its fascinating story and intriguing news are revealed in a Tablet article titled Proust&amp;rsquo;s Madeleine Was Originally a Slice Toast.
Being the Tablet &amp;ldquo;a daily online magazine of Jewish news, ideas, and culture&amp;rdquo;, it makes sense that a good part of the article focuses on Proust&amp;rsquo;s ambivalence about his Jewishness. Still, there are many other interesting tidbits to be learned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Beginner&#39;s Guide to Miles Davis</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/a-beginners-guide-to-miles-davis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/a-beginners-guide-to-miles-davis/</guid>
      <description>Sam Enright assembled a friendly Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Miles Davis. If you&amp;rsquo;ve always been curious about jazz but never really managed to get into it, then this resource might serve as a good starting point. I cannot say I&amp;rsquo;m one hundred per cent aligned with his choices, but we&amp;rsquo;re close. One remarkable statement I concur with is this one:
 Jazz is so interesting to me because of its fusion of intricate underlying structure with improvisation and spontaneity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linus Torvalds addresses an anti-vaxxer</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/linus-torvalds-addresses-an-anti-vaxxer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/linus-torvalds-addresses-an-anti-vaxxer/</guid>
      <description>Linus Torvalds&amp;rsquo; reply to an anti-vaxxer on the Linux kernel list is a must-read. Pre-2018, Linus would have destroyed the poor chump. He&amp;rsquo;s discouraging further discussion (Kernel list is not the place for that) while providing crystal clear and detailed mRNA vaccine information, all without renouncing to an opening salvo of his good-ole, grumpy style.
As John Gruber affirms, this is one rant we can all get behind.
Subscribe to the newsletter, the RSS feed, or follow @nicolaiarocci on Twitter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Source: What Happens When the Free Lunch Ends?</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/open-source-what-happens-when-the-free-lunch-ends/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/open-source-what-happens-when-the-free-lunch-ends/</guid>
      <description>The article I&amp;rsquo;m linking today is authored by Aaron Stannard and focuses on the drama currently going on in the .NET Open Source ecosystem. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there. A dependency we took aeons ago goes unmaintained or changes its licensing model. Why does this happen? Because at some point, projects need to become sustainable or else they fail.
 [&amp;hellip;] it&amp;rsquo;s inexpensive for maintainers to support a small number of users with relatively similar demands - but once a project achieves critical mass and the demand on the maintainers exceeds their desire to supply, something will have to give.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Wars 2002 and its connection to Eve Online</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/trade-wars-2002-and-its-connection-to-eve-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/trade-wars-2002-and-its-connection-to-eve-online/</guid>
      <description>Trade Wars 2002 was a great 1991 online game I hosted on one of my BBSes back in the day. Not sure if it was Lorien or Phoenix BBS; it might have been the latter given the game&amp;rsquo;s release date. I totally forgot TW2002 until yesterday when I spotted this 1991: Trade Wars 2002 article on the 50 Years of Text Games newsletter.
I humbly confess that, until yesterday, I never made the obvious connection between TW2002 and Eve Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Programming and Writing</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/on-programming-and-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/on-programming-and-writing/</guid>
      <description>My brilliant friend Salvatore Sanfilippo (otherwise known as antirez of Redis fame) has an interesting write-up on his website. How similar is programming to prose writing? After getting his own feet wet with novel writing, he is convinced that the two activities share many common traits.
 One year ago I paused my programming life and started writing a novel, with the illusion that my new activity was deeply different than the previous one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grim Secret of Nordic Happiness</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-grim-secret-of-nordic-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-grim-secret-of-nordic-happiness/</guid>
      <description>For decades Scandinavian countries have been renowned for their educational systems, low levels of corruption, sustainable economy, social justice, overall quality of life. According to Jukka Savolainen on Slate, the reason why Finns have now been dominating the World Happiness Report four years in a row has little to do with these factors and more with their life expectations.
Savolainen perspective is interesting because he is a Finn living in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earth Restored</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/earth-restored/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/earth-restored/</guid>
      <description>Only 24 people have journeyed far enough to see the whole Earth against the black of space. The images they brought back changed our world. Here is a selection of the most beautiful photographs of Earth — iconic images and unknown gems — digitally restored to their full glory.
 Toby Ord&amp;rsquo;s recent Earth Restored project is a must-see.
Subscribe to the newsletter, the RSS feed, or follow @nicolaiarocci on Twitter</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding is favoured over subtracting in problem solving (and software systems)</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/adding-is-favoured-over-subtracting-in-problem-solving-and-software-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/adding-is-favoured-over-subtracting-in-problem-solving-and-software-systems/</guid>
      <description>Consider the 10x10 grids of green and white boxes below. How would you make them symmetrical? Most people would add green boxes to the emptier half of the grid rather than remove them from the fuller half. Even when the latter would have been more efficient.
The case, along with a similar problem revolving around the stability of a peculiar lego structure, is reported by an intriguing Nature article on the topic of psychology and human behaviour.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQLite is the only database you will ever need in most cases</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/sqlite-is-the-only-database-you-will-ever-need-in-most-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/sqlite-is-the-only-database-you-will-ever-need-in-most-cases/</guid>
      <description>The name SQLite is a nice name, but the &amp;ldquo;lite&amp;rdquo; part is misleading, it sounds like it is only useful for tiny things - which is very wrong. SQLite should be named AwesomeSQL, because that is what it is. SQLite is probably the only database you will ever need in most cases
 Yeah. This article resonates with me. SQLite is the de-facto standard engine for embedded systems. But it should also be the go-to database for all those websites and services that don&amp;rsquo;t need to scale to multiple machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Real Book (of Jazz)</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-real-book-of-jazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-real-book-of-jazz/</guid>
      <description>What a fascinating read. It sits right at the intersection of two of my (too many) vicious interests: Jazz music and books.
 Since the mid-1970s, almost every jazz musician has owned a copy of the same book. It has a peach-colored cover, a chunky, 1970s-style logo, and a black plastic binding. It’s delightfully homemade-looking—like it was printed by a bunch of teenagers at a Kinkos. And inside is the sheet music for hundreds of common jazz tunes—also known as jazz “standards”—all meticulously notated by hand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quicker window snapping on macOS</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/quicker-window-snapping-on-macos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/quicker-window-snapping-on-macos/</guid>
      <description>I never see my macOS desktop. It&amp;rsquo;s always cluttered with way too many open windows. When I spot those fantastic, tidy and clean Desktops on the internet, I envy their owners. I wonder if and how they manage to keep those desktops tidy like that the whole workday. It must feel so good.
I try to keep my windows well arranged. The typical setup might be two windows, from two different apps, tiled side by side.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hitchhiker’s Guide to Online Anonymity</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-online-anonymity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-online-anonymity/</guid>
      <description>This is a maintained technical guide that aims to provide introduction to various online tracking techniques, online id verification techniques and guidance to creating and maintaining (truly) anonymous online identities including social media accounts safely and legally. No pre-requisites besides English reading are required.
 At a glance, I suspect most people will be tempted to dismiss The Hitchhiker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Online Anonymity as borderline paranoia. But make no mistake, it is a great resource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get better at programming by learning how things work</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/get-better-at-programming-by-learning-how-things-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/get-better-at-programming-by-learning-how-things-work/</guid>
      <description>When we talk about getting better at programming, we often talk about testing, writing reusable code, design patterns, and readability. All of those things are important. But in this blog post, I want to talk about a different way to get better at programming: learning how the systems you’re using work! This is the main way I approach getting better at programming.
 Once again, Julia Evans has great sensible advice up on her site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write libraries, not services? Not so fast</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/write-libraries-not-services-not-so-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/write-libraries-not-services-not-so-fast/</guid>
      <description>Write libraries instead of services is an interesting article I read a while ago. I cannot get it off my head. In an attempt to clear up my mind, I decided to sit down and write about it. I have been writing libraries for a good part of my life. Most of my earlier dev-work resides on thousands of computers in the form of libraries. More recently, I have been writing and deploying remote services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Pusher of Digital Memorabilia</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/my-pusher-of-digital-memorabilia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/my-pusher-of-digital-memorabilia/</guid>
      <description>If you are a grumpy old geek like me, you are probably a sucker for vintage computer games too. I don&amp;rsquo;t play games. Not anymore. I still enjoy reading about them, though. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s mostly nostalgia. I also believe that the mid-80s up to the mid-90s really was the golden age of computer games. In my book, innovation started with Infocom&amp;rsquo;s text adventures and soft-ended with Origin&amp;rsquo;s Ultima Online. After that, it&amp;rsquo;s been a constant evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write Good Software Documentation</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/how-to-write-good-software-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/how-to-write-good-software-documentation/</guid>
      <description>There is a secret that needs to be understood in order to write good software documentation: there isn’t one thing called documentation, there are four. They are: tutorials, how-to guides, technical reference and explanation. They represent four different purposes or functions, and require four different approaches to their creation. Understanding the implications of this will help improve most documentation - often immensely.
 I dig Daniele Procida&amp;rsquo;s take on writing good software documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Shrink a WSL2 Virtual Disk</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/how-to-shrink-a-wsl2-virtual-disk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/how-to-shrink-a-wsl2-virtual-disk/</guid>
      <description>I discovered you can use the &amp;ldquo;diskpart&amp;rdquo; tool to compact a VHDX. This allows you to shrink a WSL2 virtual disk file, reclaiming disk space. It appeared to work for me without any data corruption, taking the file size down from 100GB to 15GB. (source)
 I adore Parallels &amp;ldquo;reclaim disk space&amp;rdquo; feature. Just the other day, I got back 70GB off my Windows Guest in a breeze. I&amp;rsquo;m coming from VirtualBox, where reclaiming disk space is a significant pain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Have to Write As Though Your Parents Are Dead</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/you-have-to-write-as-though-your-parents-are-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/you-have-to-write-as-though-your-parents-are-dead/</guid>
      <description>The Literary Hub has a great short interview with Ian McEwan.
 What’s the best writing advice you’ve ever received? When I was living in London at the start of my career in the mid-1970s, I became friends with Philip Roth, who took an avuncular interest in my work. Where many others thought my writing was wild and weird, he thought I wasn’t being wild enough. He once came to my apartment and spread the typescript of my first novel (The Cement Garden) over the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleaning Up Your Postgres Database</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/cleaning-up-your-postgres-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/cleaning-up-your-postgres-database/</guid>
      <description>I am an application/backend developer who has to quibble with databases more often than desired. I can get my way around Postgres pretty well, but I can always use a hint or two, especially when it comes to fine-tuning and performance.
I stumbled upon Cleaning Up Your Postgres Databases. It offers useful advice on spotting performance bottlenecks in your Postgres database. Take the cache and index hit queries, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semantic Versioning Will Not Save You</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/semantic-versioning-will-not-save-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/semantic-versioning-will-not-save-you/</guid>
      <description>The always brilliant Hynek recently posted Semantic Versioning Will Not Save You. Primarily targeted at consumers of SemVer-versioned packages, it is full of insightful advice.
From my perspective as an open-source maintainer, I can tell you that versioning is hard. Judging when a new release is going to break backward compatibility is not as simple as it might seem on the surface, and Hynek does a great job explaining why. Sometimes it is also hard for me to tell if a change in a codebase classifies as a new feature, small improvement, or fix—subtle differences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse engineering an obfuscated codebase and fixing it in the process</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/reverse-engineering-an-obfuscated-codebase-and-fixing-it-in-the-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/reverse-engineering-an-obfuscated-codebase-and-fixing-it-in-the-process/</guid>
      <description>Today&amp;rsquo;s mandatory reading is How I cut GTA Online loading times by 70%.
As someone who&amp;rsquo;s been fighting the protection/obfuscation cat &amp;amp; mouse game for twenty+ years, let me tell you one thing. The way this guy reverse-engineered parts of the GTA5 codebase and then proceeded to single-handly triage and fix a long-standing (7+ years) performance issue is simply mindblowing. All he had to work with were heavily obfuscated dlls. This also shows how we, the protectors, are always playing a losing game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the CEO and founder of Signal</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/on-the-ceo-and-founder-of-signal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/on-the-ceo-and-founder-of-signal/</guid>
      <description>Last weekend&amp;rsquo;s reading list also included Taking Back Our Privacy, yet another1 New Yorker piece but this time signed by Anna Wiener. This article is a long-read on Moxie Marlinspike, co-founder and CEO of Signal. Moxie is a childhood nickname. That alone signals (pun intended) an original personality. I mean, how many times have you heard of a CEO going by his childhood nickname?
Indeed the personal story of Marlinspike, along with that of the ascent of Signal, is fascinating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Activists Who Embrace Nuclear Power</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-activists-who-embrace-nuclear-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-activists-who-embrace-nuclear-power/</guid>
      <description>Today, my Sunday long-reading list included New Yorker&amp;rsquo;s The Activists Who Embrace Nuclear Power by Rebecca Tuhus-Dubrow. Can nuclear power possibly be a viable solution for climate change? Twenty or even ten years ago, my answer would have been a big fat No. Today? Not so sure anymore.
 Today, the looming disruptions of climate change have altered the risk calculus around nuclear energy. James Hansen, the NASA scientist credited with first bringing global warming to public attention, in 1988, has long advocated a vast expansion of nuclear power to replace fossil fuels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Minutes to Make You Love Classical Music</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/five-minutes-to-make-you-love-classical-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/five-minutes-to-make-you-love-classical-music/</guid>
      <description>I already mentioned what background music (or sounds) I like when I am coding. In that list, I included classical music. I know classical is not exactly a favorite. Not in my field, at least. I suspect the vast majority of people disregard it in advance, not really knowing what they&amp;rsquo;re missing out on, just because, well, you know, it&amp;rsquo;s dinosaurs stuff. If you are among them, you should reconsider and repent your sins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lasting Lessons of John Conway&#39;s Game of Life</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-lasting-lessons-of-john-conways-game-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-lasting-lessons-of-john-conways-game-of-life/</guid>
      <description>In March 1970, Dr. John Conway sent the &amp;ldquo;fatal&amp;rdquo; (as he later referred to it) letter to Martin Gardner. He was submitting ideas for Gardner&amp;rsquo;s Mathematical Games column in Scientific American.
The New York Times features a good article on the fifty-year parable of The Game of Life. What&amp;rsquo;s appreciable, they asked some of Life&amp;rsquo;s most steadfast friends to reflect upon its influence and lessons over half a century. Among them, Brian Eno, who, being Brian Eno, has some smart things to say:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Homebrew breaks your Python virtual environment</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/when-homebrew-breaks-your-python-virtual-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/when-homebrew-breaks-your-python-virtual-environment/</guid>
      <description>Ever had your old, trusty Python virtual environment fail on you? I sure did. Sometimes, when I activate or switch between virtual environments, I get the following error:
$ workon eve dyld: Library not loaded: @executable_path/../.Python  I never really took the time to look into it. When this happens, because I am in a rush (and because I am a lazy old fart), I shrug it off, recreate the virtual environment on the spot, and get back to work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong opinions on software development</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/strong-opinions-on-software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/strong-opinions-on-software-development/</guid>
      <description>After six years in the field, Chris has shared his strong opinions on software development practices, languages, and methodologies. I like his attitude. Willingness to continuously put one&amp;rsquo;s personal views under scrutiny, eventually adapting or even changing them as needed, is not a common trait. Not in our field. While I generally agree with most of his opinions, I feel the urge to comment on a few of them.
 Typed languages are better when you&amp;rsquo;re working on a team of people with various experience levels</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Unbundling according to Benedict Evans</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-great-unbundling-according-to-benedict-evans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-great-unbundling-according-to-benedict-evans/</guid>
      <description>As a non-native English reader, I had to look up the true meaning of &amp;ldquo;Unbundling&amp;rdquo; as a neologism. According to Wikipedia
 Unbundling is a neologism to describe how the ubiquity of mobile devices, Internet connectivity, consumer web technologies, social media and information access in the 21st century is affecting older institutions (education, broadcasting, newspapers, games, shopping, etc.) by &amp;ldquo;break[ing] up the packages they once offered (possibly even for free), providing particular parts of them at a scale and cost unmatchable by the old order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The unreasonable effectiveness of simple HTML</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-unreasonable-effectiveness-of-simple-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/the-unreasonable-effectiveness-of-simple-html/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve seen other articles pointing the finger at unnecessarily bloated websites. Terence Eden&amp;rsquo;s On the unreasonable effectiveness of simple HTML deserves mention, I think, for two reasons. First, the delivery is incredibly effective. Second, it is effective because of the storytelling.
By enveloping the message into an original short, touching story, he achieves two goals. First, he captures the reader&amp;rsquo;s attention; second, he makes the experience memorable. Please, go and read it; I&amp;rsquo;ll wait here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the short, tormented life of Phil Katz</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/on-the-short-tormented-life-of-phil-katz/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/on-the-short-tormented-life-of-phil-katz/</guid>
      <description>Bless the Internet Archive and its Wayback Machine. With it, we can go back in time and read The short, tormented life of computer genius Phil Katz, an unusually detailed and accurate article published in the April 14, 2000 issue of the Milwaukee Journal Sentinel.
 When he was found dead April 14, Phil Katz was slumped against a nightstand in a south side hotel, cradling an empty bottle of peppermint schnapps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>