<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reviews on Nicola Iarocci</title>
    <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/tags/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reviews on Nicola Iarocci</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://nicolaiarocci.com/tags/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: We Have Always Lived in the Castle</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/book-review-we-have-always-lived-in-the-castle/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/book-review-we-have-always-lived-in-the-castle/</guid>
      <description>I came back to reading Shirley Jackson almost by coincidence. I had just finished watching The Haunting of Hill House, and, as I always do with stuff that tickles my curiosity, I was doing a little research on it. That&amp;rsquo;s how I learned that the TV Series is loosely based on a novel by the same name written by&amp;hellip; Shirley Jackson.
Still imbued by the TV Series&amp;rsquo;s atmospheres, now knowing about its connection with Jackson, I was ready for another dive into her literature of psychological suspense and terror.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: The Water Dancer</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/book-review-the-water-dancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/book-review-the-water-dancer/</guid>
      <description>The Water Dancer is the debut novel for Ta-Nehisi Coates, an author and journalist best known for his nonfiction works. Set in a slave plantation located in pre-civil war Virginia, this is a bold and ambitious story about slavery. From the editor website:
 Young Hiram Walker was born into bondage. When his mother was sold away, Hiram was robbed of all memory of her—but was gifted with a mysterious power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Erebus, The Story of a Ship</title>
      <link>https://nicolaiarocci.com/book-review-erebus-the-story-of-a-ship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 07:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nicolaiarocci.com/book-review-erebus-the-story-of-a-ship/</guid>
      <description>I finished reading Erebus: The Story of a Ship by Michael Palin, an excellent book on the dramatic adventures of the HMS Erebus with her sister ship, the HMS Terror, first in James Clark Ross&amp;rsquo;s Antarctic expedition of 1839-43, and then during Franklin’s ill-fated Arctic expedition in search of the Northwest Passage. I knew Michael Palin as a member of the Monty Python comedy group. As it turns out, since 1980, he has also made many travel documentaries and books.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>